<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rachel S. Gross</title>
    <link>https://whysinati.github.io/hugo-rg/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Rachel S. Gross</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://whysinati.github.io/hugo-rg/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Curriculum Vitae</title>
      <link>https://whysinati.github.io/hugo-rg/curriculum-vitae/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://whysinati.github.io/hugo-rg/curriculum-vitae/</guid>
      <description>EDUCATION  Ph.D. University of Wisconsin-Madison, 2017 M.A. University of Wisconsin-Madison, 2012 B.A. University of Puget Sound, 2008 EMPLOYMENT  Assistant Professor of History, University of Colorado Denver, 2020 – present Postdoctoral Teaching, Research, and Mentoring Fellow, Davidson Honors College, University of Montana, 2017 – 2019 PUBLICATIONS  Articles  “Ultralight: Commercializing Lightweight Backpacks for Long Distance Hiking,” forthcoming, The International Journal of the History of Sport “Logos on Everest: Commercial Sponsorship of Expeditions, 1950-2000,” forthcoming, Enterprise &amp;amp; Society “Layering for a Cold War: The M-1943 Combat System, Military Testing, and Clothing as Technology,” Technology and Culture 60, no.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://whysinati.github.io/hugo-rg/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://whysinati.github.io/hugo-rg/about/</guid>
      <description>Rachel S. Gross is an environmental and cultural historian of the modern U.S. and an Assistant Professor of History at the University of Colorado Denver . In 2019 she was a Carson Fellow at the Rachel Carson Center in Munich and a Postdoctoral Teaching, Research, and Mentoring Fellow at the Davidson Honors College of the University of Montana .
She was awarded the 2018 Herman E. Krooss Prize for Best Dissertation in Business History from the Business History Conference for her writing on the history of outdoor clothing and gear in the U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://whysinati.github.io/hugo-rg/home/projects/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://whysinati.github.io/hugo-rg/home/projects/projects/</guid>
      <description>DO I NEED THIS FILE? NO, delete!
My book project, Buckskin to Gore-Tex: The Outdoor Industry in American History, explores the cultural, intellectual, and environmental history of the outdoor gear industry.
Learn more about this work on the Highlander Podcast’s History of Gear Series or watch this lecture from the Rachel Carson Center in 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://whysinati.github.io/hugo-rg/home/subheader/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://whysinati.github.io/hugo-rg/home/subheader/</guid>
      <description>From Stetson hats and buckskin suits to army surplus tents and Gore-Tex rain jackets, outdoor gear and its marketing in catalogs, stores, and guidebooks are a means to understanding how Americans strove for an authentic mastery of the outdoors. The argument: Consumption became central to Americans’ goal of mastering the outdoors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curated History</title>
      <link>https://whysinati.github.io/hugo-rg/home/media/media4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://whysinati.github.io/hugo-rg/home/media/media4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Checkout these cool exhibits and tours to learn more about the fascinating history of outdoor gear.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streaming</title>
      <link>https://whysinati.github.io/hugo-rg/home/media/media3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://whysinati.github.io/hugo-rg/home/media/media3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;See live presentations, interviews and other videos that bring history alive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>https://whysinati.github.io/hugo-rg/home/media/media1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://whysinati.github.io/hugo-rg/home/media/media1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dr. Gross in action, instructing on a number of historical topics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing</title>
      <link>https://whysinati.github.io/hugo-rg/home/media/media2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://whysinati.github.io/hugo-rg/home/media/media2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pause for a moment to read and ponder about the next time you explore the great outdoors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>